RG 116, Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford
Connecticut State Library
Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford records
1832, 1900, 1924-1936
bulk 1924-1936
Connecticut State Library
Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford
4 cubic feet
The preamble to the Constitution of the Society of Descendants of the Founders of Hartford gives the following description of the objectives of the organization: “We, descendants of the Founders of Hartford, do hereby constitute ourselves the Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford, in order to further the worthy celebration of the three hundredth anniversary of the founding of the city... that original documents and historical works of merit relating to the founders and the early history of the city may be published; and to see to it that relics of the founders and of the early history of the city may be preserved.”
RG116
T001462
Historical Note
The preamble to the Constitution of the Society of Descendants of the Founders of Hartford gives the following description of the objectives of the organization: “We, descendants of the Founders of Hartford, do hereby constitute ourselves the Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford, in order to further the worthy celebration of the three hundredth anniversary of the founding of the city... that original documents and historical works of merit relating to the founders and the early history of the city may be published; and to see to it that relics of the founders and of the early history of the city may be preserved.”
Scope and Contents
Records include scrapbooks, guest books, pamphlets, maps, genealogical charts, and photographs.
Related Material
None.
Index Terms
Organizations:
Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford
Subjects:
Society of the Descendants of the Founders of Hartford -- Records and correspondence; Hartford (Conn.) -- History -- Societies, etc
Document Types:
Scrapbooks; Maps; Pamphlets; Correspondence; Visitors' books; Genealogies; Photographs
Restrictions on Access
Some of these records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1832; 1900,; 1924-1936
  - 1. Scrapbooks, circa 1935-1936; 3 volumes (Box 1)
    Contains miscellaneous lists, correspondence, clippings and photographs.
  - 2. Guest books, 1935-1936; 2 volumes (Box 1)
  - 3. Pamphlets (Box 2)
    - Relating to the Society, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Published to commemorate Connecticut Tercentenary, 1935 (Box 2)
    - Concerning Connecticut towns and points of interest, circa 1930-1935 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1935, undated (Box 2)
    - Descriptive materials concerning Hartford, 1900, 1924-1935, undated (Box 2)
  - 5. Portfolio including maps, newspaper clippings, genealogical charts (Clark, Hooker, Thatcher, and photostats of commemorative tablets, circa 1935 (Box 3)
  - 6. Pictures
    - Photo of tablet honoring Harriet Beecher Stowe, b&w, 5 x 7 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Photo of tablet on Silas Deane House, b&w, 5 x 7 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Portrait of William Pynchon, b&w, 6.75 x 4.25 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Portrait of Archbishop Warham, from the original picture by Holbein in Lambeth Palace, color, 8 x 5 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Engraving of Battle of Lexington, re-engraved by A. Doolittle and J.W. Barber in 1832, color, 4.5 x 7.5 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Engraving: Broome in Kent, the Seat of Sir Henry Oxenden, b&w, 8.25 x 10.5 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - (Market Day in Central Square in 1780) visualized by Claude L. Yates, crayon, color, 8.75 x 22 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Reproduction of portrait of Jane Seymour by Holbein, b&w, 8 x 5.5 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Old Talcott House and the Hollister House, Glastonbury, CT, b&w, 5 x 6 in.; 2 engravings (Map-case Map case)
    - Engraving, Hartford fire, b&w, 10 x 14 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Reproductions of engravings of Charter Oak, b&w, 16.25 x 18.25 in.; 2 engravings (Map-case Map case)
    - Poem "To an Engraving of the Charter Oak" by Genevieve L. Hutchinson, b&w, 8.5 x 5.5 in. (Map-case Map case)
    - Painting of first State House on one side, and newspaper clipping on the other, 8.5 x 38.5 in. board (Item Item 4)